# Javid Chien-Hsin Hsueh

530-601-3761 https://javid.me javidhsueh@gmail.com

Javid is a senior data visualization engineer at Uber. At Uber, he builds self-service data tools to consolidate information, create exploratory data visualizations to get actionable insights and contribute efforts to open-source projects to give back to the community. He's been working in several business domains, including business intelligence, risk & safety, A/B testing, and machine learning. Expert in data visualization and UI/UX design.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Senior Software Engineer - Visualization Uber

San Francisco, CA

Feb 2016 - Present

- Leading efforts to build machine learning visualization and the machine learning platform UI "Michelangelo".
- Uber knowledge graph visualization tool which helps Risk & Safety team to investigate frauds.
- Published open source graph rendering library graph.gl (https://graph.gl), and contribute to several open-source frameworks in react-vis, deck.gl, kepler.gl
- Built a set of self-service dashboarding tools and business insight visual analytic tools.
- Lecturer for data visualization in Graduate school of management, UC Davis.

**Resident Scientist** 

**Exploratorium** 

San Francisco, CA July. 2014 - Sept. 2014

- Designed and implemented interactive visualizations of marine animal movement data sets.
- Developed an exhibit showing the migration of marine animals with tangible user interface.

**Graduate Researcher** 

**UC Davis** 

Davis, CA

Sept. 2012 - 2016

- · Worked with Prof. Kwan-Liu Ma in Visualization & Interface Design Innovation Research Group.
- Designed and implemented several interactive visualization research projects. Major topics include time series storyline, movement data analysis, dedupe problem, and user behavior analysis.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Davis, Master of Computer Science

Sept. 2012 - Feb 2016, Davis, CA

· Working with Prof. Kwan-Liu Ma in Visualization & Interface Design Innovation Research Group.

National Taiwan Normal University, Bachelor/Master of Computer Science

Sept. 2005 - Jun. 2011, Taipei

- Worked with Prof. Yung-Pin Cheng in Software Engineering Lab.
- Intrusive test automation with failed test case clustering. Outstanding research award APSEC 2011.

### RESEARCH PROJECTS

- <u>Marine animal migration visualization</u>(2015). Developed interactive data visualizations of ocean animal datasets, enabled visitors to discover patterns and engage in meaningful self-directed explorations.
- A Visual Approach for Name Disambiguation in Coauthorship Networks (2015). Developed an interactive visual tool for large coauthorship networks, to identify cases of homonymy and/or synonymy, and solve the name ambiguity problem.
- <u>Comparative Driving Behavior Visualization</u> (2014). Developed a web-based interactive system to explore and compare the driving behavior from probe data. A new visual metaphor is designed for representing driving behavior of history trips.
- Incremental Storyline Layout Algorithms for Streaming Data (2013). A set of greedy-based layout algorithm is proposed to deal with streaming data and improve the layout periodically by an extreme optimization strategy.
- Intrusive Test Automation with Failed Test Case Clustering (2011). By analyzing the execution traces of failed test cases in a daily build, the representative failed test cases are selected by proposed clustering techniques.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Chien-Hsin Hsueh, Jia-Kai Chou, Kwan-Liu Ma. A Study of using Motion for Comparative Visualization. In IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium, 2015.
- Chien-Hsin Hsueh, Jacqueline Chu, Kwan-Liu Ma, Joyce Ma, Jennifer Frazier. Fostering Comparisons: Designing an Interactive Exhibit that Visualizes Marine Animal Behaviors. In IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium, 2015.
- Christopher Muelder, Chien-Hsin Hsueh, Kwan-Liu Ma, A Visual Approach for Name Disambiguation in Coauthorship Networks. Submitted to IEEE Visual Analytics Science and Technology 2015, under review.
- Yuzuru Tanahashi, Chien-Hsin Hsueh, Kwan-Liu ma. An Efficient Framework for Generating Storyline Visualizations from Streaming Data. In IEEE Transaction on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 2015.
- Chien-Hsin Hsueh, Yung-Pin Cheng, Wei-Cheng Pan. Intrusive test automation with failed test case clustering. Outstanding research award, In ACM Proceedings of APSEC 2011, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam.
- Yung-Pin Cheng, Han-Yi Tsai, Chih-Shun Wang, Chien-Hsin Hsueh. xDIVA: automatic animation between debugging break points. In ACM Proceedings of SOFTVIS'2010. pp. 221~222, Utah, USA.